朋友们，我们继续在 Estudios AFA 与伟大的 Nicolás Tagliafico 一起参加 AFA Selection 的这一特别回合，欢迎来到随机影响。
Friends we continue in this special round here at Estudios AFA with AFA Selección with the great Nicolás Tagliafico, welcome to Random Impact.
Amigos seguimos en esta tanda especial aquí en Estudios AFA con AFA Selección con el gran Nicolás Tagliafico, bienvenido a Random Impact.
尼科你在做什么？
What are you doing Nico?
¿Qué haces Nico?
终于我们见面了。
Finally we met.
Al fin nos conocimos.
最后，通过网络，但不是亲自。
Finally, through networks, but not in person.
Al fin, por redes, pero no personalmente.
就个人而言，如果我们出去的话，我们现在就会把它扔掉，我们一直在谈论佩鲁诺的话题。
Not personally, we'll throw it away now if we get out there, we've been chatting about the Perruno topic.
No personalmente, ya lo tiramos ahora si nos sacamos allí, venimos charlando con el tema Perruno.
亲爱的，你的妻子和我的马鲁拉开始互相追随，我们刚刚收养了一只狗，你见过的我们都有你的狗
dear, your wife with my malula begins to follow each other, we just adopted a dog, we that you had seen have both of yours
caro tu mujer con málula mía empiezan a seguirse justo adoptamos una perrita nosotros que ustedes habían visto que tienen los dos suyos
这就是 Instagram 轮子的起点。
and that's where the Instagram wheel started a little.
y ahí arrancó un poco la rueda de Instagram.
他的爱……不仅仅是对狗，嗯。
The love he has... Not just for dogs, huh.
El amor que tiene... No solo por los perros, eh.
当然，对于动物来说。
Of course, for the animals.
Claro, por los animales.
是的，是的，是的，他也向我灌输了这一点。
Yes, yes, yes, he instilled that in me too.
Sí, sí, sí, me lo inculcó a mí también.
就像那个生物一样，你必须尝试...
It's like that living being that you have to try to...
Es como ese ser vivo que hay que tratar de...
并帮助您，因为不知何故您无法与我们沟通。
and help you because somehow you can't communicate with us.
y ayudarlo porque de alguna manera no se puede comunicar con nosotros.
这显然是我们对狗的爱，也是对动物本身的爱。
It is love for dogs obviously from us, but also for the animal itself.
Es amor por los perros obviamente de nosotros, pero también por el animal en sí.
多好啊！
How nice!
¡Qué lindo!
那些旅行的人现在一直和你们在一起吗？
Are they with you all the time, those who travel, for now?
¿Están con ustedes todo el tiempo, los que viajan, por ahora?
是的，到处都是。
Yes, everywhere.
Sí, a todos lados.
这是一个话题，因为它很复杂，我们很现代。
It is a topic because it is complicated, we are quite modern.
Es un tema porque es complicado, nosotros somos bastante modernos.
这要付出很多代价，例如，今天我必须在这里。
and it costs a lot, for example, today I have to be here.
y cuesta mucho, por ejemplo, hoy me toca estar acá.
卡罗曾经在这里，所以我们不得不打电话给一位朋友留在家里。
Caro was here at one point, so we have to call a friend to stay at home.
Caro en un momento estuvo acá, entonces tenemos que llamar a algún amigo para que se quede en casa.
他们在法国，狗留在那里。
They are in France, the dogs stayed there.
Ellos están en Francia, se quedaron ahí los perros.
我们不能带它们，因为这是一个 12 小时的旅程。
We cannot bring them because it is a 12-hour trip.
No los podemos traer porque es un viaje de 12 horas.
这是一个主题，是的，这是一个主题。
It's a theme, yes, it's a theme.
Es un tema, sí, es un tema.
狗旅馆，你看到了吗？
Dog hotel, did you see that?
Hotel de perro, ¿viste eso?
越来越多的“Play Friends”。
There are more and more Play Friendly.
Hay cada vez más Play Friendly.
它并没有完全封闭我。
It doesn't quite close me.
No me termina de cerrar.
如果有人可以呆在家里，请照顾他们。
If someone can stay home, take care of them.
Si alguien se puede quedar en casa, los cuida.
他们在他们的栖息地，他们想念，对吗？
They are in their habitat and they miss, right?
están en su hábitat y extrañan, ¿no?
你想念他们。
You miss them.
Ustedes los extrañan.
是的，显然。
Yes, obviously.
Sí, obvio.
但是，嘿，已经十天了。
But hey, it's ten days.
Pero bueno, son diez días.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
十天了，然后……
It's ten days and then...
Son diez días y después…
狗爱回归。
Dog love returns.
Vuelve el amor perruno.
而且你还有其他事情需要担心和集中精力，那就是这个，优先级，选择，一切。
And you have other things to worry about and concentrate on, which is this, priority, selection, everything.
Y tenés otras cosas para preocuparte y concentrarte, que es esto, prioridad, selección, todo.
当足球运动员进入球场时，生活就被遗忘了。
When a soccer player enters the field, life is forgotten.
Cuando un jugador de fútbol entra en la cancha se olvida la vida.
我的意思是，这只是球、比赛、全神贯注和再见。
I mean, it's just the ball, the game, full concentration and bye.
O sea, es solo la pelota, el partido, concentración full y chau.
是的，是的。
Yes, yes.
Sí, sí.
我认为这是关键。
I think that's key.
Creo que lo clave.
尝试保持专注于游戏。
Try to stay focused on the game.
tratar de mantenerse enfocado en el partido.
幸运的是，我在这方面做得非常好，每次进入球场时我都会全神贯注。
and it is something that luckily I do very well and every time I enter a court I am fully focused.
y es algo que por suerte me sale muy bien y cada vez que entro en una cancha estoy full enfocado.
我总是说这就像 90 场一分钟的比赛。
and I always say that it's like 90 one-minute games.
y yo siempre digo que son como 90 partidos de un minuto.
始终专注于需要做什么，无论发生什么，如果顺利，如果出错，你都必须考虑这一点。
all the time focused on what needs to be done, no matter what happens, if it goes well, if it goes wrong, you have to think about that.
todo el tiempo enfocado en lo que hay que hacer, pase lo que pase, si sale bien, si sale mal, hay que pensar en eso.
因为人们会忘记。
Because people forget.
Porque la gente se olvida.
当然，有两个人，还有这个，呃，狗，发生了其他事情，我叔叔生病了，一个家庭成员去世了。
Of course, there are two people and you have this, uh, the dogs, something else happened, my uncle got sick, a family member died.
Por supuesto, son dos personas y que vos tenés esto, uh, que los perros, que pasó otra cosa, me enfermó mi tío, se murió un familiar.
人们不知道的事情，你必须上场，你必须成为职业球员，就是这样。
Things that people don't know and you have to get on the field and there you have to be pro, that's what.
cosas que la gente no sabe y vos tenés que entrar a la cancha y ahí donde tiene que ser pro, eso es.
对我来说，保持专注对于一名足球运动员来说非常关键。
For me, it is something very key for a footballer to maintain concentration.
Para mí es algo muy clave del futbolista mantener la concentración.
分别是 90 分钟、95 分钟、100 分钟。
It's 90, 95, 100 minutes.
Son 90, 95, 100 minutos.
保持专注。
Stay focused.
Mantén la concentración.
因为最后你的体质也开始恶化，你开始疲倦。
because in the end your physique also begins to deteriorate, you start to get tired.
porque al final después también el físico empieza a mermar, te empiezas a cansar.
但如果你头脑清醒、注意力集中，那就会给你带来好处。
But if you are fresh in the head and focused, that gives you the plus.
Pero si estás fresco de la cabeza y estás enfocado, eso te da el plus.
对我来说，对于一名足球运动员来说，专注于他正在做的事情是非常重要的。
For me it is something very important for a footballer to have concentration and attention on what he is doing.
Para mí es algo muy importante en un futbolista tener la concentración y la atención en lo que se está haciendo.
听着，你还记得国家队的第一次征召吗？
Listen, do you remember the first call for the national team?
Escucha, ¿te acordás de la primera convocatoria de la selección?
是的，在澳大利亚确实如此。
Yes, in Australia it was.
Sí, en Australia fue.
但你还记得他们告诉你的那一刻吗？
But do you remember the moment when they told you...
Pero vos te acordás el momento en el que te dicen...
换句话说，我被征召加入阿根廷足球队。
In other words, I was called up to the Argentine soccer team.
O sea, fui convocado a la selección argentina de fútbol.
细节，细节，我不记得了。
Detail, detail, I don't remember.
Detalle, detalle, no me acuerdo.
但我确实记得我在独立队比赛时接到了电话。
but I do remember that I was playing here at Independiente and I got the call.
pero sí recuerdo que estaba jugando acá en Independiente y me llega el llamado.
不是直接来自教练，而是来自AFA，说
not directly from the coach, but from AFA, saying
no directamente del entrenador, sino de AFA, diciendo
他将被邀请参加当时是 2018 年 6 月的会议。
that he was going to be called for the date that at that time was June 2018.
que iba a estar convocado para la fecha que en ese momento era junio de 2018.
或者2017年3月或者2017年6月，我记不太清了。
Or March 2017 or June 2017, I don't remember exactly.
O marzo de 2017 o junio de 2017, no me acuerdo exactamente.
什么也没有。
And nothing.
Y nada.
纯粹的幸福，因为那一刻我一直想要它。
Pure happiness because I had been wanting it for a long time at that moment.
Felicidad pura porque lo venía deseando hace mucho tiempo en ese momento.
它是给我的，它是给我的，但是，好吧，我也理解选择......
and it was given to me, it was given to me, but well, also understanding that the selection...
y se me daba, se me daba, pero bueno, también entendiendo que la selección...
每个人的愿望都是来并留下来。
Everyone's wish is to come and stay.
El deseo de todos es venir y quedarse.
过来留下来吧。
Come and stay.
Llegar y quedarse.
当然，来一场比赛，然后发生什么就发生什么。
Of course, come to a game and then whatever happens happens.
Claro, venir a un partido y después que pase lo que pase.
你担心这只是一场游戏，仅此而已？
And you were afraid that it was a game and nothing more?
¿Y tenías miedo de que fuera un partido y nada más?
不，不是因为我确信我必须这样做。
No, not because I was convinced that I had to be.
No, no porque estaba convencido de que tenía que estar.
我必须在那里，我必须做这件事，我想把它做好
that I had to be there and I had to do it and I wanted to do it well
que tenía que estar y lo tenía que hacer y lo quería hacer bien
它发生了，就这样发生了，直到今天，每一种情况都是我回来了，我回来了。
And it happened, it happened like that, and it is to this day that also, every situation is I'm back and I'm back.
Y se dio, se dio así, y es hasta el día de hoy que también, cada situación es estoy de vuelta y estoy de vuelta.
总有一天，情况会对我们造成不好或好的影响。
Someday the situation is going to take us badly and well.
Algún día nos va a llevar mal la situación y bueno.
换句话说，你不会失去价值。
In other words, you don't lose value.
O sea, no le perdés el valor.
不，不，不是那样。
No, no, not that.
No, no, eso no.
对我来说这也是关键。
For me it is the key too.
Para mí es lo clave también.
别习惯了。
Don't get used to it.
No acostumbrarse.
如果你放松下来并说，啊，是的，选择，我就会去。
If you relax and say, ah, yeah, the selection, I'll go.
Si te relajas y dices, ah, sí, la selección, voy.
不。
No.
这是一个很好的观点，我正在和你们很多人交谈，对吧？
That's a good point, I'm talking to a lot of you, right?
Ese punto es bueno, estoy hablando con muchos de ustedes, ¿no?
和亚历克斯，和太田，和一切。
With Alex, with Ota, with everything.
Con Alex, con Ota, con todo.
再次感谢媒体的尼科和爸爸，他们管理了这些精彩的笔记，这对我来说是一种荣幸。
Once again thanks to Nico from the press and Dady who have managed these spectacular notes, which for me is an honor.
Una vez más gracias a Nico de prensa y a Dady que han gestionado estas notas espectaculares, que para mí es un honor.
但每次都赋予它价值
but this thing of giving it value and that every time
pero esta cosa de darle valor y de que cada vez
因为这很困难，所以你也习惯了获胜。
Because it's difficult, you also get used to winning.
Porque es difícil, también te acostumbras a ganar.
你们经常赢得一切。
You guys won everything very often.
Ustedes ganaron todo muy seguido.
当你输球时，对于这支几乎不输球的球队来说一定很奇怪。
and when you lose it must be strange for this team that almost doesn't lose.
y cuando perdés debe ser raro para esta selección que casi no pierde.
是的，就像最后你把标准设置得越来越高，当发生不同的事情时，就像......
Yes, it's like in the end you set the bar higher and higher and when something different happens it's like a...
Sí, es como que al final pones la vara cada vez más alta y cuando sucede algo diferente es como un...
这里发生了什么？
What happened here?
¿Qué pasó acá?
但这是完全正常的。
But it's totally normal.
Pero es totalmente normal.
这是一项有三种结果的足球运动，任何一种都可能发生。
It is a soccer sport where there are three results, any one can happen.
Es un deporte de fútbol donde hay tres resultados, se puede dar cualquiera.
我们做了一些可能不寻常的事情，才赢得了这么多、如此频繁的胜利。
We did something perhaps abnormal to have won so much, so often too.
Nosotros hicimos algo quizás anormal de haber ganado tanto, tan seguido también.
但对我来说，这也是团队所拥有的心态。
but for me it is the mentality that the group has as well.
pero para mí es la mentalidad que tiene el grupo también.
而且我觉得...
And I feel that...
Y siento de que...
他们很少，那些失败帮助我们......
They are few, those defeats help us...
que son pocas, esas derrotas nos ayudan a...
再次接触地面并跳得越来越高。
to touch the ground again and jump higher and higher.
a tocar tierra de vuelta y a saltar cada vez más alto.
始终需要的挺举和挺举...
The clean and jerk that is always needed to...
El envión ese que se necesita siempre para...
保持谦虚，专注于我们想要的东西。
to stay humble, to stay focused on what we want.
para mantenerse humilde, para mantenerse enfocado en lo que queremos.
斯卡洛尼在这一切中到底有多恶心？
How gross is Scaloni in all that?
¿Cuán grosso es Scaloni en todo eso?
这些目标的很大一部分已经实现，因为最终
and it is a large part of these objectives that were achieved because in the end
y es gran parte de estos objetivos que se lograron porque al final
球员、教练、技术人员齐心协力，共同实现所取得的成就。
Together players, coaches, technical staff where everything is unified to achieve what is achieved.
Juntos jugadores, entrenadores, cuerpo técnico donde se unifica todo para lograr lo que se logra.
这需要双方的努力，我们很好地收到了他的信息，我们执行了它。
It takes both parties and we received his message very well, we carried it out.
Se necesita de las dos partes y su mensaje lo recibimos muy bien, lo llevamos a cabo.
最终这就是我们所取得的成果。
and in the end that's what achieved the results we achieved.
y al final eso es lo que logró los resultados que logramos.
球队的身份和比赛风格非常明显。
The identity, the style of play that the team has is very marked.
La identidad, el estilo de juego que tiene la selección es muy marcado.
他总是重复这句话，让我们把传球放在一起，让我们比赛，让我们比赛，让我们比赛，最终这就是让我们变得强大的原因。
And he always repeats it, let's put together passes, let's play, let's play, let's play, that in the end that's what makes us strong.
Y él siempre lo repite, el de juntemos pases, juguemos, juguemos, juguemos, que al final eso es lo que nos hace hacer fuertes.
这就是发生的事情。
and that's what happens.
y es lo que pasa.
最后，如果你看到国家队的大部分目标，那就是
In the end, if you see the majority of the goals that the national team has, they are
Al final, si ves la mayoría de los goles que tiene la selección, son
组合传球、比赛、控球。
Putting together passes, playing, having the ball.
Juntando pases, jugando, teniendo la pelota.
它们是良好创造的美好目标。
They are nice goals of good creation.
Son lindos goles de buena creación.
这就是团结。
That is unity.
Eso es unidad.
很少有反击说射门就进球。
Very few counterattacks that say a shot and a goal.
Muy pocos de contragolpe que digan pelotazo y gol.
好吧，这就一劳永逸地确定了这场比赛，这场原本应该输掉又恢复的阿根廷比赛。
Well, that identifies the game once and for all, the Argentina game that was supposed to have been lost and recovered.
Bueno, eso identifica el juego de una vez por todas, el juego de Argentina que se supone se había perdido y se recuperó.
所以就像我们收到了这条消息一样，我们收到得很好，而且玩家也有很好的感觉，这对我来说也很关键。
So it's like we received that message, we received it well and it also has a good feeling with the player, that for me is key too.
Entonces es como que ese mensaje lo recibimos, lo recibimos bien y también tiene el buen feeling con el jugador, eso para mí es clave también.
在你的位置上，你的偶像是谁？
Who is your idol in your position?
¿Quién es tu ídolo en tu posición?
我总是说卷皮，我小时候总见过他。
I always say that Juanpi, I always saw him when I was a kid.
Siempre digo que Juanpi, siempre lo veía cuando era chico.
更重要的是，有几次我和他交谈并说我们必须将横向联合放在一起
What's more, the times I have talked with him and said we have to put together the lateral union
es más las veces que he charlado con él y dije tenemos que armar el sindicato de laterales
我喜欢边工会。
I like the side union.
Me gusta el sindicato de laterales.
这是一种反对派，有时...
It is an opposition that sometimes...
Es una oposición que a veces...
左和右，对吗？
Left and right, right?
Izquierdo y derecho, ¿no?
两侧。
Sides two.
Laterales dos.
是的，我们将它们添加到权利中。
Yes, we add them to the rights.
Sí, los sumamos a los derechos.
因为他们可能是两个不同的伟人。
Because they can be two different greats.
Porque pueden ser dos grandes diferentes.
好吧，还有pupi，另一个……
Well, the pupi too, another...
Bueno, el pupi también, otro...
当我还是个孩子的时候，我看到这两个人就好像他们是一个例子一样
of my age when I was a boy I saw the two then as if they were a bit of an example
de mi edad cuando yo era chico veía a los dos entonces como que fueron un poco el ejemplo
但是，是的，是的，它有帮助。
But yes, yes, it helped.
Pero sí, sí, ayudó.
今天你32岁了，对吗？
Today you are 32 years old, right?
Hoy tenés 32 años, ¿no?
好的。
GOOD.
Bien.
你对足球的看法比22岁时更好吗？
Do you see football better than you did at 22?
¿Ves mejor el fútbol que a los 22?
放吧。
Put it.
Ponele.
你是在告诉我我是怎么看他的，他当时是什么样子的吗？
Are you telling me how I saw him, how he was at the time?
¿Vos me estás diciendo cómo lo veía yo, cómo estaba en su momento?
如果你今天在球场上比十年前更好地阅读足球。
If you read football better today on the field than 10 years ago.
Si vos lees mejor el fútbol hoy en la cancha que hace 10 años.
是的，完全可以。
Yes, totally.
Sí, totalmente.
在那个年纪，10年前，我开始学习
At that age, 10 years ago, I was beginning to learn
En esa edad, hace 10 años atrás, yo empezaba a aprender
一切都是战术性的，一切都与战略有关。
Everything tactical, everything related to strategy.
Todo lo táctico, todo lo relacionado a lo estratégico.
足球本身，今天我变得越来越
of football itself and today I am becoming more and more
del fútbol en sí y hoy en día estoy siendo cada vez más
我会讲得更详细，因为将来我也想成为一名教练。
I'm going into more detail because in the future I would like to be a coach as well.
Voy más al detalle porque en un futuro me gustaría ser entrenador también.
所以好像我也会在另一边多走一些路。
So it's like I'm also going a little more on the other side.
Entonces es como que también estoy yendo un poco más del otro lado.
来自战术家。
From the tactician.
Del táctico.
是的，不仅要学习，还要帮助。
Yes, not only to learn but also to help.
Sí, no solo de aprender sino también de ayudar.
所以是的，是的，但是从很小的时候开始，即使是22岁......
So yes, yes, but from a very young age, even at 22...
Entonces sí, sí, pero desde muy chico, incluso a los 22 ya...
在这方面我有非常聪明的教练。
I had had very intelligent coaches in that regard.
Había tenido entrenadores muy inteligentes en ese aspecto.
我总是提到里卡多·拉戈尔佩，他是我的教练，在这个意义上给我留下了深刻的印象。
I always name Ricardo Lagolpe, who was a coach for me who marked me in that sense.
Siempre lo nombro a Ricardo Lagolpe, que fue un entrenador para mí que me marcó en ese sentido.
我有很多经历让我对战术产生了兴趣。
and I had many that made me gain that taste for tactics.
y tuve muchos que me hicieron agarrar ese gustito por lo táctico.
梅西段落。
Messi paragraph.
Párrafo Messi.
我问了大家。
I asked everyone.
Se lo pregunté a todos.
梅西为什么这么恶心？
Why is Messi so gross?
¿Por qué Messi es tan grosso?
你们是精英，在世界上最好的联赛中踢球，与他分享，你们有什么别人没有的？
You who are elite, who play in the best leagues in the world, who share with him, what do you have that others don't have?
Ustedes que son de elite, que juegan a mejores ligas del mundo, que comparten con él, ¿qué tiene que otros no tienen?
或者什么让你惊讶？
Or what amazes you?
¿O qué te asombra?
除了它必须发挥的所有自然品质之外
well in addition to all that natural quality that it has to play
bueno además de toda esa calidad natural que tiene para jugar
踢足球，拥有控制力，运球，一切。
to play football, to have the controls it has, to dribble it has, everything.
jugar al fútbol, para tener los controles que tiene, para los regates que tiene, todo.
我认为他有智慧
I think he has an intelligence
Creo que tiene una inteligencia
这也有点我们讲战术的意思，这不正常，哪里
This is also a little bit about what we talk about tactics, which is not normal, where
esto un poco también de que hablamos táctica, que no es normal, donde
她假装你正在看台上观看比赛，你看，你正在从上方观看比赛，所以我走上空间。
She pretends that you are watching the game from the stands, you see, that you are watching it from above, so I go up and space.
Hace de cuenta que vos ves el partido desde la tribuna, viste, que la ves desde arriba, así subo y espacio.
无论在哪里，我的平衡都是如此。
everywhere, my balance is that.
en todos lados, mi equilibrio está aquel.
嗯，他从球场内看到了这一点。
Well, he sees it from inside the court.
Bueno, él desde adentro de la cancha lo ve.
他从平淡中看到了我们从观众那里看到的东西。
He sees from the plain what we see from the audience.
Él ve desde el llano lo que por ahí nosotros vemos de la platea.
比方说，从无人机上。
From a drone, let's say.
Desde un drone, digamos.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
我相信他能察觉到一切，并且有能力……
I believe that he detects everything and has that ability to...
Yo creo que él lo detecta todo y tiene esa capacidad para...
知道空间在哪里，知道拿球时的心理速度......
to know where the spaces are, to know that mental speed when you have the ball...
para saber de dónde están los espacios, para saber de que esa rapidez mental cuando tenés la pelota...
它很难。
It's difficult.
Es difícil.
当他把球传给我时，我只是想看看我把球传给了谁，仅此而已。
When he gives me the ball I'm trying to see who I give it to, nothing more.
Yo cuando me da la pelota estoy tratando de ver a quién se la doy, nada más.
她像盖德雷兹一样思考着两三步。
She is thinking two or three steps like a gedrez.
Ella está pensando dos o tres pasos como una gedrez.
正在考虑提前三步。
is thinking three steps ahead.
está pensando tres pasos adelante.
我给你胡说八道，但这并不重要，当我们这样做的时候
I give you that nonsense but it doesn't matter, when we did
Te doy ese una boludez pero no importa, cuando hicimos
里克尔梅告别。
Riquelme's farewell.
La despedida de Riquelme.
我留在草地上，在平原上。
I stayed in the grass, on the plain.
Yo me quedé en el pasto, en el llano.
你不看足球，每个人都去球场上从电视或观众席上观看比赛。
You don't watch football, everyone goes to the field and watches it from the TV or from the audience.
Uno no ve fútbol, todo el tipo va a la cancha y lo ve desde la tele o desde la platea.
所以当你从平原上看到它时，你就看不到它的另一面了。
So when you see it from the plain, you can't see it on the other side.
Entonces cuando lo ves desde el llano, del otro lado no se ve.
我说，这是一场致敬比赛，对吗？
And I said, it was a tribute match, right?
Y yo decía, era un partido de homenaje, ¿no?
Leo触球，我很惊讶地看到他在那里，速度非常接近
Leo touched the ball, I was surprised to see him there, very close to the speed of
que leo tocaba la pelota me sorprendió verlo ahí cerquita la velocidad de
他在给之前就已经给了通行证。
He already gave the pass before giving it.
El ya dio el pase antes de darlo.
确切地说，我告诉你的是，他们说他在四处走动，他在阅读一切......
Exactly, what I'm telling you, what they say is that he's walking around, he's reading everything...
Exacto, esto que te digo, eso que dicen que está caminando por ahí, él está leyendo todo...
竞争对手移动到哪里，他们就能找到空间。
where rivals move, where they can find space.
donde se mueven los rivales, donde pueden encontrar espacio.
十分钟后他就发现了……
and in ten minutes he already found out that...
y por ahí en diez minutos ya sacó de que...
当他接球时，右后卫正在逼近并用左腿在那里踢球。
When he receives, the right-back is closing and has his left leg to play it there.
Cuando él recibe, el lateral por derecho está cerrando y tiene la pierna izquierda para jugarlo allá.
诸如此类的事情...
Things like that one...
Cosas así que uno...
与...与...
with... with...
con... con...
凭借这种天赋，他做了他所做的事情。
With that talent he does what he does.
Con ese talento hace lo que hace.
他会给出好的建议吗？
Does he give good advice?
¿Da buenos consejos?
是的，显然。
Yes, obviously.
Sí, obvio.
他所说的一切都是我们正在谈论的事情的一部分。
Everything he says is a little bit of what we are talking about.
Cada cosa que dice es un poco lo que estamos hablando.
他已经在那里看到了，所以……你必须听他的。
He already saw it there, so... You have to listen to him.
Él por ahí ya lo vio, entonces... Tenés que escucharlo.
是的，你必须听它。
Yes, you have to listen to it.
Sí, tenés que escucharlo.
如果你不听，那就是愚蠢的。
If you don't listen, that's stupid.
Si no escuchás eso es un gil.
我不知道这是否愚蠢，但最终就像......
I don't know if that's stupid, but in the end it's like...
No sé si eso es un gil, pero al final es como que...
然后事情发生了，你说，看，我是对的。
And then it happens and you say, see, I was right.
Y después pasa y dices, viste, tenía razón.
他是对的，利奥。
He was right, leo.
Tenía razón, leo.
听着，去计划吧，你和卡罗谁更浪漫？
Listen, going to the plan, who is more romantic, you or Caro?
Escucha, yendo al plano, ¿quién es más romántico, vos o Caro?
亲密拍摄。
Intimate shot.
Plano íntimo.
我相信我。
I believe I.
Yo creo yo.
你更浪漫吗？
Are you more romantic?
¿Vos sos más romántico?
是的，我比较浪漫。
Yes, I'm more romantic.
Sí, soy más romántico.
注意，向卡罗莱纳报告！
Attention, report to Carolina!
¡Atención, denuncia para Carolina!
她已经知道的就是一切！
What she already knows is everything!
¡Ella lo que ya sabe es todo!
我在外面很浪漫，因为我是一个更喜欢惊喜的人。
I'm romantic out there because I'm more of a surprise person.
Yo por ahí soy romántico porque soy más de las sorpresas.
所以这也更浪漫一点。
So that's a little more romantic too.
Entonces eso es un poco más romántico también.
请给我一个惊喜。
Please throw me a surprise.
Por favor, tirame una sorpresa.
一个可以算数的。
One that can count.
Una que pueda contar.
不，例如...
No, for example...
No, por ejemplo...
我的第一个经历是一次惊喜的假期旅行，我告诉他我们去某某地方。
One of the first ones I had was a surprise vacation trip that I told him let's go to such and such a place.
una de las primeras que tuve fue un viaje sorpresa de vacaciones que le dije vamos a tal lugar
因为我已经从中得到了一切，而且这是我们的第一个假期。
because I had already gotten everything out of it and it was our first vacation.
porque ya le había sacado todo y eran las primeras vacaciones nuestras.
一起。
together.
juntos.
我说的是2000年，大约10年前。
I'm talking about 2000, about 10 years ago.
Hablo de 2000, hace como 10 años atrás.
那样的话有点奇怪。
Like that was kind of weird.
Como eso fue algo raro.
这就是你的魔力。
So there's your magic.
Así que ahí está tu magia.
你会像这样抛出一些惊喜。
You throw some surprises like that.
Tirás unas sorpresas de ese estilo.
而我还有的就是，我不着急，很多时候……
And what I also have is that I am not anxious and many times...
Y lo que tengo también es que no soy ansioso y muchas veces...
我把东西放在屋子里什么的，这对她来说很难......
I keep things inside the house or something and it's hard for her...
guardo cosas dentro de la casa o algo y a ella le cuesta mucho...
她必须告诉我，你明白吗？
She has to tell me, you see?
Ella me lo tiene que contar, ¿viste?
他告诉我...我给了你这个，他告诉我。
He tells me... I gave you this, he tells me.
Me cuenta... Te regalé esto, me dice.
别告诉我，让我吃惊。
Don't tell me, surprise me.
No me lo contés, dámelo a sorpresa.
那个女人也对我做了同样的事。
The woman does the same to me.
La mujer me hace lo mismo.
你的生日是18号，可以在16号过吗？
Your birthday is the 18th, can you have it on the 16th?
Tu cumpleaños es el 18, ¿te lo podés dar del 16?
不！
¡No!
现在是18号了，16号买的就留着吧。
It's the 18th, if you bought it on the 16th, keep it.
Es el 18, si lo compraste el 16, guardalo.
当然，保存并立即给我。
Sure, save and give it to me right away.
Claro, guarda y dámelo en el momento.
我的意思是，他当然有焦虑。
I mean, of course, he has anxiety.
O sea, claro, tiene ansiedad.
我比较冷静，所以就像，你是如何忍受这一切的？
I be calmer, so it's like, how did you manage to put up with this?
Yo sé más tranquilo, entonces es como, ¿cómo hiciste para aguantarte esto?
听我说，抢劫的话题上了新闻，对吗？
Listen to me, the topic of robberies was in the news, right?
Escuchame, fue en una noticia el tema de los robos, ¿no?
而他们却遭受了...
And they suffered...
Y que sufrieron...
里昂还是巴黎？
Lyon or Paris?
El Lyon o en París?
埃尔里昂。
El Lyon.
所以她回来了，她往返于阿姆斯特丹。
So she came back, she goes back and forth to Amsterdam.
Entonces ella volvió, ella va y viene a Ámsterdam.
我要澄清一下，因为结果有点奇怪。
I'm going to clarify it because it came out kind of weird.
Lo voy a aclarar porque quedó medio raro.
首先，他们不是抢劫，而是企图。
First, they weren't robberies, they were attempts.
Primero no fueron robos, fueron intentos.
没有发生盗窃事件。
There was no theft.
No hubo nada de robo.
抢劫企图。
Robbery attempt.
Intento de robo.
他们走进屋子。
They went into the house.
Se metieron a la casa.
他们进入房子，拉响警报后离开。
They entered the house, sounded the alarm and left.
Entraron a la casa, sonaron la alarma y se fueron.
第一个是你，第二个是她。
The first was you and the second was her.
La primera estabas vos y la segunda ella.
第二个是一个人，因为我在玩。
The second one was alone because I was playing.
La segunda estaba ella sola porque yo estaba jugando.
正确的。
Correct.
Correcto.
他们知道我比赛的时间，他们走进屋子，狗开始吠叫，因为他们没有携带武器。
They knew the time of my game, they entered the house, the dogs started barking because they were not armed.
Sabían el horario de mi partido, entraron a la casa, los perros empezaron a ladrar porque no estaban al arma puesta.
她警觉起来，看到了他们，也拉响了警报，他们就离开了。
She became alert, saw them, sounded the alarm as well and they left.
Ella se alertó, los vio, hizo sonar alarma también y se fueron.
啊，但是你感到恐惧吗？
Ah, but the scare that grips you?
Ah, ¿pero el susto que te agarra?
她害怕自己孤身一人。
The scare for her that she was alone.
El susto para ella que estaba sola.
通常我们都会比赛，如果她不去球场或其他什么事情，她就会留下来。
Normally we play and if she doesn't go to the court or something she stays.
Normalmente nosotros jugamos y si ella no va a la cancha o algo se queda.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
独自一人很害怕。
And it's a scare to be alone.
Y es un susto estar sola.
这是去年的 2023 年。
This was in 2023, last year.
Esto fue en 2023, el año pasado.
因此，我们已经在那所房子里说，好吧，让我们尝试寻找其他东西，一个更安静、更安全的公寓。
So already in that house we said, well, let's try to find something else, an apartment that's a little quieter, safer.
Entonces ya en esa casa dijimos, bueno, vamos a tratar de buscar otra cosa, un departamento algo más tranquilo, más seguro.
事实也是如此。
And so it was.
Y así fue.
现在我住在公寓里。
Now I am living in an apartment.
Ahora estoy viviendo en un departamento.
她说了一点。
She told this a little.
Ella contó un poco esto.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
所以现在我遇到的问题就像病毒一样蔓延开来。
So now it's like it went viral that I had problems.
Entonces, ahora es como que se viralizó de que tenía problemas.
不。
No.
不，相反，我们很棒，我们很好。
No, on the contrary, we are great, we are fine.
No, al contrario, estamos geniales, estamos bien.
当时...
At the time...
En su momento...
她去了阿姆斯特丹、里昂，这样当我出去玩等时候，她就不会一个人在家里呆那么久。
She made trips to Amsterdam, to Lyon, so she wouldn't be alone for so long in the house when I went out to play and so on.
hacía viajes a Amsterdam, a Lyon, para no quedarse sola tanto tiempo en la casa cuando yo salía a jugar y demás.
我们说阿姆斯特丹是因为你在那里踢了很长时间，所以他很熟悉，所以当你旅行的时候他已经在那里有用了，这样就不会在里昂孤单了。
We say Amsterdam because you played there for a long time, so he was familiar, so when you traveled he was already useful there, so as not to be alone in Lyon.
Decimos Amsterdam porque jugaste mucho tiempo ahí, entonces él era familiar, entonces cuando vos viajabas sirve ya para allá, para no estar solo en Lyon.
这让我害怕，这已经很清楚了，所以今天在埃尔里奥部门我们很平静。
It scared me, it is well clarified, so today in the El Río Department we are calm.
me ha dado miedo, está bien aclarado, así que hoy Departamento El Río estamos tranquilos.
所以没问题。
So no problem.
Así que no hay problema.
听着，你出去遛狗吗？
Listen, do you go out to walk the dogs?
Escucha, ¿salís a pasear a los perritos?
除此之外，我们靠近里昂的一个非常大的公园。
On top of this we are close to a very large park in Lyon.
Encima de esto estamos cerca de un parque muy grande de Lyon.
而且……没什么，我们步行十分钟就到了。
And... nothing, we have it a ten minute walk away.
Y... nada, lo tenemos a diez minutos caminando.
但你是特拉科吗？
But are you tlacico?
¿Pero vos sos tlacico?
不，我不感兴趣。
No, I'm not interested.
No, no me interesa.
我知道，我希望你能通过它们。
I know, I want you to pass them.
Ya sé, yo quiero que los pasés.
我想说的是...
What I'm saying is...
Lo que digo es...
还有塔利亚，热情的狗。
There is Taglia, passion of the dog.
Ahí está Taglia, pasión del perro.
他们经常让你受苦吗？莱昂的生活怎么样？
Do they screw you a lot or what is life like in León?
¿Te jodan mucho o cómo es en León la vida?
不错。
Pretty good.
Bastante bien.
这位法国人并不是那么狂热的足球迷。
The Frenchman is not that big of a football fan.
El francés no es tan futbolero.
而且很恭敬，他们也不打扰。
and it is quite respectful, they do not bother.
y es bastante respetuoso, no molestan.
是的，它不会让我发疯。
Yeah, it doesn't drive me crazy.
Sí, no me vuelve loco.
即使我必须在阿根廷这里这样做，我也会这样做。
Even if I had to do it here in Argentina, I do it.
Incluso si lo tendría que pasar acá en Argentina, lo hago.
这会更困难，因为狗会等待。
It would be more difficult because the dogs would be waiting.
Sería más difícil porque los perros estarían esperando.
在这里，您将有两个步行架的 50 张照片。
Here you would have 50 photos for two walking frames.
Aquí tendrías 50 fotos por dos cuadros de paseo.
我比狗
I than the dogs.
Yo que los perros.
当然，狗最适合你。
Of course, dogs are perfect for you.
Claro, los perros te van con el cielo.
瓦尔，宾夕法尼亚州。
Val, pa.
Vale, pa.
但是，是的，我尝试...这很好，这是一个出去一点的计划。
But yes, I try to... It's good, it's a plan to get out a little.
Pero sí, trato de... Está bueno, es un plan para salir un poco.
深吸一口气，做点不同的事情，想一想……
take a breath, do something different, think about...
tomar aire, hacer algo diferente, pensar en...
在露天并对待不同的东西。
in the open air and treated something different.
en el aire libre y tratadas algo distinto.
动物之爱将延伸到更多被收养的狗身上，还是人类婴儿即将到来？
Animal love is going to extend to more adopted dogs or are human babies coming?
amor animal se va a extender a más perrito adoptado o ya van a venir los bebitos humanos
不，我知道如果我们要找一只狗，这次就必须适应它。
No, I know that if we are going to look for a dog it has to be adapted this time.
No, yo sé que si vamos a buscar un perro tiene que ser adaptado esta vez.
更重要的是，我告诉卡罗，这对她来说很难，但我见过很多......
What's more, I told Caro that it's hard for her, but I've seen many who...
Es más, le dije a Caro que a ella le cuesta mucho, pero he visto muchos que...
它们很大，已经很旧了，也许在某个时候我想要一些……小旧罐子。
They are big, they are already older and I would like maybe at some point some... Little old jars.
que son grandes, que ya son mayores y me gustaría quizás en algún momento algunos... Tarritos viejitos.
近年来，是的。
In recent years, yes.
A los últimos años, sí.
但也一定很痛苦。
But it must be painful too.
Pero debe ser doloroso también.
不，但我推荐它。
No, but I recommend it.
No, pero te lo recomiendo.
我们已经拥有了他们离开此生的尊严。
We already had the dignity with which they leave this life.
Nosotros tuvimos ya la dignidad con la que se van de esta vida.
换句话说，作为成年祖父母，这是你能做的最好的事情。
In other words, being adult grandparents, it is the best thing you can do.
O sea, siendo abuelitos adultos es lo mejor que le podés hacer.
所以，这就是它所在的地方。
So, that's where it is.
Entonces, por ahí eso.
嗯，我喜欢这个主意。
Well, I like the idea.
Bien, me gusta la idea.
那么显然...然后我会帮助你做任何你想做的事。
Then obviously... Then I'll help you with whatever you want.
Después obviamente… Después te ayudo con lo que quieras.
戴尔.
Dale.
这对你有帮助。
That helps you.
Eso te ayuda.
然后，显然我们要...
And then, obviously we're going to...
Y después, obviamente vamos a...
迟早我们必须开始扩大家庭。
Sooner or later we have to start expanding the family.
Tardo o temprano tenemos que empezar a agrandar la familia.
不仅是狗，还有...
Not only with dogs, but also...
No solo con perros, sino también...
也不作为一个程序。
Nor as a procedure.
Tampoco como un trámite.
显然，显然，我愿意。
Obviously, obviously, I would like to.
Obvio, obvio, me gustaría.
他们还年轻，还有时间。
They are young, there is still time.
Son jóvenes, todavía hay tiempo.
是的，是的，但是我们愿意，我们觉得我们也准备能够开始了。
Yes, yes, but we would like to, we feel that we are also prepared to be able to start.
Sí, sí, pero nos gustaría, sentimos que estamos también preparados para poder empezar.
好，好，好。
Good, good, good.
Bien, bien, bien.
你还缺少什么？
What are you missing?
¿Qué te falta?
在生活层面或足球层面。
at the life level or at the football level.
a nivel vida o a nivel fútbol.
你总是设定目标，无论你喜欢与否，你...
You always set goals, whether you like it or not, you...
Uno se va siempre poniendo objetivos, quieras o no, uno...
我认为，在足球层面上，足球运动员最大的愿望已经实现了。
At the football level, what the footballer, the greatest desire, was achieved, I think.
A nivel fútbol, se logró lo que el futbolista, el máximo anhelo, creo.
但俱乐部层面总有一些东西。
But there is always something there at the club level.
Pero siempre por ahí a nivel club tiene alguna cosita.
例如，我很想赢得冠军联赛。
I would love to win the Champions League, for example.
Me encantaría ganar la Champions, por ejemplo.
亚历克西斯也告诉了我。
Alexis also told me.
Alexis también me dijo.
俱乐部 我希望能够为足球界最大的俱乐部之一效力。
club I would love to be able to play for one of the biggest clubs in football.
club me encantaría poder jugar en uno de los más grandes del fútbol.
我必须在荷兰最大的纳亚打球。
I have had to play in Naya, which is the largest in Holland.
Me ha tocado jugar en Naya, que es el más grande de Holanda.
里昂也是法国最大的城市之一。
Lyon is one of the biggest in France too.
El Lyon es uno de los más grandes de Francia también.
但在全球层面上，我希望能够再迈出一步，看看我是否有机会参加英超联赛或其他联赛。
But at a global level I would love to be able to take one more step to see if I get a chance in the Premier League or something.
pero a nivel mundial me encantaría poder dar un paso más a ver si me toca en la Premier League o algo.
这将取决于事态的发展。
That will depend on how the situation develops.
Eso dependerá de cómo se dé la situación.
在生活层面上，我一直在努力学习，但没有……
And at a life level I try to learn all the time, there is no...
Y a nivel vida trato de aprender todo el tiempo, no hay...
幸运的是，我们做自己喜欢的事情，我们对足球充满热情，我们把它当作一份工作，但最终它是……
Luckily, we do what we like, we are passionate about football and we do it as a job, but in the end it is something that...
Nosotros por suerte hacemos lo que nos gusta, somos apasionados del fútbol y lo hacemos como un trabajo, pero al final es algo que...
我们喜欢做并且一直想要，或者就我而言，我尝试这样做
that we love to do and always want or in my case I try to
que nos encanta hacer y siempre queremos o en mi caso trato de
我很好奇，我尝试学习一切，将来我想成为一名教练，但是......
I am very curious, I try to learn everything and in the future I want to be a coach, but...
Soy muy curioso, trato de aprender de todo y en un futuro quiero ser entrenador, pero...
没有什么。
Nothing.
Nada.
演奏乐器。
Play an instrument.
Tocar un instrumento.
一切，一切。
Everything, everything.
De todo, de todo.
你能学到的就越多。
The more you can learn.
Cuanto más se puede aprender.
你焦躁不安吗？
Are you restless?
¿Sos inquieto?
你是小主播吗？
Are you a little streamer?
¿Sos un poco streamer?
covid阶段，我们该怎么办，嗯，就是从这个流趋势开始的
The covid stage, what do we do, well it started with this stream trend
La etapa de covid, de qué hacemos, bueno empezó con esta moda del stream
怎么办？
How to do?
¿Cómo hacer?
这是在社交网络上与我的人民、社区联系的唯一方式。
It is the only way to connect on social networks with my people, with the community.
Es la única manera de conectarme en redes sociales con mi gente, con comunidad.
我说，我们就这么做吧。
I say, let's do it.
Digo, vamos a hacerlo.
我只需要说话，你说。
I just have to talk, you said.
Solo tengo que hablar, dijiste.
起初是非常困难的。
At first it is very difficult.
Al principio es muy difícil.
事实上，我很惊讶，因为我对着摄像机说话。
The truth is that I was surprised because I talk to a camera.
La verdad que me sorprendí porque hablo con una cámara.
该死，然后你放手，这很好，因为最终它也会帮助你
Damn, then you let go and it's good because in the end it also helps you
carajo, después ya te soltás y está bueno porque al final también te ayuda
不知不觉中它对你的笔记有帮助。
Unconsciously it helps you in notes.
Inconscientemente te ayuda en notas.
你放得更多，你不需要……当然，当然。
You let go more, you don't need... Of course, of course.
Uno se suelta más, no necesita... Claro, claro.
你没有羞耻感，麦克风，摄像机。
You don't have the shame, the microphone, the camera.
No tenés como la vergüenza, el micrófono, la cámara.
他总是和播放磁带的足球运动员发生关系。
And he always screws with the footballer who plays the cassette.
Y siempre se jode con el futbolista que se pone el cassette.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
它们是人们没有意识到但有帮助的事情。
They are things that one does not realize but that help.
Son cosas que uno no se da cuenta pero que ayudan.
好吧，我认为你今天根本没有表现出来。
Well, I don't think you've put yourself out there today at all.
Bien, yo no considero que hoy te hayas puesto el cacer para nada.
我喜欢你将成为一名教练，我看到你一直踢到 38、40、37 岁……Puppi Sanetti？
I like that you are going to be a coach, I see you playing until you are 38, 40, 37... The Puppi Sanetti?
Me gusta que vas a ser entrenador, te veo jugando hasta los 38, 40, 37… A los Puppi Sanetti?
致普皮·萨内蒂。
To the Puppi Sanetti.
A los Puppi Sanetti.
进而...
And then...
Y después...
那么不，让我们看看，我会喜欢的。
Then no, let's see, I would love it.
Después no, a ver, a mí me encantaría.
国家队教练组，从这里开始，你喜欢吗？
The national team's coaching staff, started here, would you like it?
El cuerpo técnico de la selección, empezado acá, ¿te gustaría?
这就是为什么我告诉你我很想开始教练课程。
That's why I tell you that I would love to start the coaching course.
Por eso te digo que me encantaría empezar el curso de entrenador.
我必须这样做，我正要开始它，但我还没有完成学业。
I have to do it, I was going to start it and I hadn't finished school.
Tengo que hacerlo, lo iba a empezar y no había terminado el colegio.
所以，当然，我还没有完成学业，我小时候就离开了学校。
So, of course, I hadn't finished school, I left it when I was a kid.
Entonces, claro, no había terminado el colegio, yo lo dejé cuando era chico.
高中你留下了什么？
What did you leave, high school?
¿Qué dejaste, la secundaria?
我高中毕业并在 2021 年美洲杯帆船赛上完成学业。
I left high school and finished it at the 2021 America's Cup.
dejé la secundaria y en la Copa de América 2021 lo terminé.
我记得我是自由地做的。
I remember that I did it freely.
Me acuerdo que lo hice a modo libre.
我放弃了自由和给予的科目。
And I gave up free and giving the subjects.
Y rendí libre y dando las materias.
德国人，当然是佩塞拉，我的搭档，记得有人在早上 7 点叫醒我，因为我已经制定了欧洲赛程。
Germán, surely Pesela, who is my partner, remembered someone who had woken me up at 7 in the morning because I have set the European schedules.
Germán, seguramente Pesela, que es mi compañero, se acordaba de alguna que me la hubiera levantado a las 7 de la mañana porque yo he puesto los horarios de Europa.
当然，当时我必须在阿根廷，早上七点起床去参加考试或类似的事情。
Of course, at that time I had to be here in Argentina and I got up at seven in the morning to take an exam or something like that.
Claro, en ese momento me tocó estar acá en Argentina y me he levantado a las siete de la mañana para rendir un examen o algo así.
但我完成了。
But I finished it.
Pero lo terminé.
感谢上帝，我完成了它，现在我可以开始参加教练课程了。
Thank God I finished it and now I can start taking the coaching course.
Gracias a Dios lo terminé y ahora puedo empezar a hacer el curso de entrenador.
这是完成学业的一个很好的借口，我想参加这门课程，但在那之后，谁又能说呢？
It's a good excuse to finish school and I would like to take the course but after that, who's to say?
Es una buena excusa para terminar el colegio y me gustaría hacer el curso pero después, ¿quién te dice?
我不知道我想要什么。
I don't know what I would like.
No se sabe que me gustaría.
我们必须尽快完成。
Quickly we have to finish.
Rápido que tenemos que terminar.
一个词定义了
A word that defines
Una palabra que defina
成为世界冠军。
be world champion.
ser campeón del mundo.
它是独一无二的。
It's unique.
Es único.
并不是唯一一个，而是因为有好几位选手赢得过这一奖项。
Not really the only one, but because there are several players who have won it.
En realidad único no, pero porque hay varios jugadores que lo han ganado.
不，但这是你的感觉。
No, but it's your feeling.
No, pero es tu sentimiento.
它可以是骄傲、幸福、喜悦……所有这些。
It can be pride, happiness, joy... All of them.
Puede ser orgullo, felicidad, alegría... Todas.
全部。
All.
Todas.
我不能告诉你一个。
I can't tell you one.
No te puedo decir una.
因为到达那里的自豪感和所有的努力......
because the pride of having gotten there and all the effort that was...
porque el orgullo de haber llegado hasta ahí y todo el esfuerzo que se...
为了到达那里必须做什么，度过职业生涯中最美好的时刻的幸福。
what had to be done to get there, the happiness of having had the best moment of my career.
que se tuvo que hacer para llegar hasta ahí, la felicidad de haber pasado el mejor momento de mi carrera.
因为今天我很想拥有一台时光机，回到2022年12月18日，那就太好了。
because today I would love to have a time machine and go back to December 18, 2022, it would be great.
porque hoy me encantaría tener una máquina del tiempo y volver al 18 de diciembre de 2022, sería genial.
所以有很多很多的词来表达这一点。
So there are many many words for that.
Entonces hay muchas muchas palabras para eso.
理想的肉末？
Ideal minced meat?
¿Picadito ideal?
Pudol 5，你和另外四个人的生活。
Pudol 5, you and four more of life.
Pudol 5, vos y cuatro más de la vida.
你可以选择任何你想要的人。
You can choose whoever you want.
Podes elegir a quien quieras.
球员、兄弟、表兄弟、叔叔、爸爸。
Players, brothers, cousins, uncles, dads.
Jugadores, hermanos, primos, tíos, papás.
另外四个人是谁？
Who are the other four?
¿Quiénes son los otros cuatro?
很难，但是...
Difficult, but...
Difícil, pero...
我可以选择谁？
Who could I choose?
¿A quién podría elegir?
我们选择Leo是因为我们在那里已经有优势了。
We chose Leo because we already have an advantage there.
A Leo lo elegimos porque ahí ya tenemos ventaja.
就不能选梅西吗？
Can't you choose Messi?
¿No se puede elegir a Messi?
每个人都带着梅西，算了吧。
Everyone carries Messi, forget it.
Todos llevan a Messi, olvídate.
是的，是的，选择它。
Yes, yes, choose it.
Sí, sí, élégilo.
梅西和沃斯。
Messi y vos.
好吧，我可以放……让我们看看，我可以放我的两个兄弟。
Well, and I can put... Let's see, I could put my two brothers.
Bueno, y puedo poner a... A ver, podría poner a mis dos hermanos.
他踢过足球但没能第一次踢球。
who played soccer and didn't get to do it first time.
que jugaron al fútbol y no llegaron a hacerlo a primera.
还有两名后卫，所以我们选择三名后卫。
and the two defenders too, so we go with three defenders.
y los dos defensores también, así que vamos con tres defensores.
是的，是的，可能是这样。
Yes, yes, it could be.
Sí, sí, podría ser.
离开大家兄弟，放飞自己和梅西。
Leave everyone brothers, let yourself go and Messi.
Deja a todos hermanos, vos suelto y Messi.
你缺守门员吗？
Are you missing a goalkeeper?
¿Te falta arquero?
是的，是的，确实如此。
Yes, yes, true.
Sí, sí, verdad.
我们把图画放在上面，什么也没有，就是这样。
And we put the drawing on it, and nothing, that's it.
Y al que le ponemos el dibujo, y nada, ya está.
除非你有一个儿时的朋友，如果他是一个伟大的弓箭手？
Unless you have a childhood friend if he is a great archer?
¿Salvo que tengas un amigo de la infancia si este es un arquerazo?
不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不不，不，不，不，不，不。
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,  no, no, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
我认为我有优势，但我认为他们两个也选择了一切。
I think I have the advantage, but I think they are the two who also choose everything.
Yo creo que saco ventaja, pero yo creo que son los dos que también eligen todo.
我们稍后会看到。
We'll see it later.
Después lo veremos.
好吧，我喜欢肉末。
Okay, I liked the minced meat.
Está bien, me gustó el picadito.
我们已经到了终点。
We have reached the end.
Hemos llegado al final.
Mate Pampa 官方一直陪伴着我们。
Mate Pampa Official always accompanies us.
Mate Pampa Oficial nos acompaña siempre.
世界冠军。
World Champions.
Campeones del mundo.
特别版。
Special edition.
Edición especial.
适合您，当然，它是根据您的伴侣的场合进行调整的
for you and of course it is tuned for the occasion this is your mate
para ustedes y por supuesto que está tuneada para la ocasión este es tu mate
壮观的潘帕斯大草原伴侣。
of spectacular pampas mate.
de mate de pampa espectacular.
太感谢了。
Thank you so much.
Muchas gracias.
尼科特拉菲科，世界冠军。
Nico Trafico, world champion.
Nico Trafico, campeón del mundo.
嘿嘿，到底好不好？
Hey, is it okay or not?
Eh, ¿está bien o no?
多好啊。
How nice.
Qué lindo.
就是这个，非常好。
This is it, very good.
Es esta, muy bien.
很漂亮，市场上最好的。
Beautiful, the best on the market.
Hermoso, lo mejor del mercado.
不，那是你的礼物。
No, that's your gift.
No, ese es tu regalo.
还有来自迪士尼的昂贵的特殊许可。
And expensive, special license from Disney.
Y a caro, licencia especial de Disney.
我们要给她这个，也是 Mate Pampa 的，我不会打开它让你拿给她。
We are going to give her this one, also from Mate Pampa, I won't open it for you to take it to her.
Le vamos a regalar este, también de Mate Pampa, no te lo abro para que se lo lleves a ella.
来吧，我就这样把它关起来。
Come on, I keep it closed like this.
Dale, lo llevo así cerradito.
告诉他这是除了你之外的惊喜，别说是我送给你的。
Tell him it's a surprise apart from you, don't say I gave it to you.
Decíle que es una sorpresa aparte tuya, no digas que te lo regale yo.
如果我没有看到它……不，不，我什么都没做。
If I don't see it... No, no, I didn't do anything.
Si no lo vea... No, no, no hice nada.
最后我没有做笔记，我什么也没做。
In the end I didn't make a note, I didn't do anything.
Al final no hice nota, no hice nada.
亲爱的，我给你带来了这个。
My love, I brought you this.
Mi amor, te traje esto.
不，我们在美国的时候，我出去度假了……
No, the time we were in the United States, I took a getaway and...
No, la vez que estuvimos en Estados Unidos, me hice una escapada y...
昨天你来到老妇人家时，她会把它给你。
She would give it to you yesterday, when you came to the old woman's house.
Ella te lo daría ayer, cuando vienes a la casa de la anciosa.
尼科，很高兴我的朋友。
Nico, a pleasure my friend.
Nico, un placer amigo.
谢谢你所做的一切，非常友善，完全天才。
Thank you for everything, very kind, total genius.
Gracias por todo, muy amable, genio total.
尼科·塔利亚菲科 (Nico Tagliafico) 与我们一起在 Random Infobike 工作。
Nico Tagliafico with us at Random Infobike.
Nico Tagliafico con nosotros en Random Infobike.